<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AutoScrollRecyclerView</string>
    <string name="text_training">
        Please read this form carefully.  The purpose of this form is to provide you with important
        information about taking part in a research study. If any of the statements or words in
        this form are unclear, please let us know. We would be happy to answer any questions.
        If you have any questions about the research or any portion of this form, please contact
        us.  Taking part in this research study is up to you.
        If you decide to take part in this research study we will ask you to electronically sign
        this form. The purpose of this study is to learn if data collected through a smartphone
        application (app) from your phone may be helpful in understanding more about patterns in
        social activity. About 50 participants will take part in this study. The user must have an
        Android smartphone to participate. This study involves taking a set of online questionnaires
        at the start of a 14-day study period, at the start of which you will download an app to
        your smartphone and answer short surveys on the app three times per day.
        This app was developed by computer scientists and psychologists at Boston University and
        is used for research only. The apps collect information in several different ways:
        The app will ask you to complete brief sets of questions about where you are and who
        you are with.  This is called active data collection and you can decide whether or
        not you wish to complete the survey at time of prompting. The app will automatically
        collect: Location information gathered by your phone\’s location sensor/global positioning
        (GPS) sensors. Activity type collected by your phone\'s accelerometer (walking, biking,
        driving, etc.). App-usage, specifically how much time is spent using other apps on your
        phone. Audio data, specifically a yes-no classification of whether or not the audio
        collected is of a conversation, based on audio features (qualities of your voice and others
        that tell us if you may be in a conversation), not language content.  We expect that you
        will be in this research study for approximately 14 days during which you are being asked
        to test a smartphone app. Before the 14-day period, we will ask you to complete a brief set
        of questionnaires (15-20 min), and will then provide you instructions for downloading the
        app on your phone. You are being asked to test the app for 14 days.  At the start of the
        14 day period we will ask you to complete a set of questionnaires online (15-20 min),
        and download the study app. During this 14-day period you will be prompted to take brief
        (less than 5 minute) smartphone assessments, three times per day. As a whole, the study
        will take no longer than 3 hours of your time. You can decide if you want to complete the
        surveys prompted at multiple times per day, which actively collect information from you.
        The app will offer you surveys about the type of place you are in, the type of people
        (if any) you are around, and questions about recent interactions with others. These surveys
        will pop up as reminders on your phone. You are free to either take these surveys or choose
        to ignore them and not take them. It is important to understand that for the 14 days you
        are in this study the app will passively collect data in the background several different
        ways. One type of data is location (GPS) data from your phone even if you are not using
        your phone. GPS stands for global positioning system and allows the phone to know where
        you are located and stores this data; GPS is usually accurate to within 10 feet. This app
        will collect GPS data constantly and securely send that information to our computers.
        The app will also be collecting your physical activity (walking, biking, driving, etc.)
        through your phone\'s accelerometer, and will collect information on how much time you
        spend using other apps on your phone; specifically, the percentage of time spent on
        social media apps, the amount of time spent on calls, number of texts sent, and number of
        videos taken. The actual content of this activity will NOT be collected. Lastly, the app
        will use your phone\'s microphone to intermittently collect audio from your environment.
        This audio data itself will not be stored, rather the app will simply assign a value to
        how likely it is that the audio was of a conversation. This yes-no probability value will
        be the data point that is securely sent to our computers. Your data will not be monitored
        in real time, meaning locations, activity, app-use, and audio data will only be reviewed
        retrospectively, after your participation is complete. Even if you decide not to complete
        the daily questionnaires, GPS, app usage and audio will continue to be collected during
        the 14-day study period. If you wish to no longer participate in the study, you will need
        to formally withdraw by contacting the Principal Investigator (contact info listed on first
        and last pages of this document) and uninstalling the app. We will keep the records of this
        study confidential. We will assign you a unique study ID code for the research information
        that we collect and no identifying information will be included with the data. The secured
        SONA systems will contain the link between your first name and your study ID code. However,
        this will not be accessible to study staff members actively analyzing data, and will no
        longer be accessible to anyone on the research team once data collection is complete. We
        will make every effort to keep your records confidential. However, there are times when
        federal or state law requires the disclosure of your records. We will make every reasonable
        effort to protect the confidentiality of your research information. However, it might be
        possible that a civil or criminal court might demand the release of identifiable research
        information. If compelled by a Massachusetts or federal judge to disclose information
        we have collected about you, we may need to release your identifiable information.
        We will make every effort to keep your records confidential.  However, there are times
        when federal or state law requires the disclosure of your records. The following people
        or groups may review your study records for purposes such as quality control or safety:
        The Researcher and any member of his research team. The Institutional Review Board at
        Boston University. The Institutional Review Board is a group of people who review human
        research studies for safety and protection of people who take part in the studies. Federal
        and state agencies that oversee or review research. The study data will be stored on secure
        servers with no identifying information, and access will only be given to researchers on
        this project.  The results of this research study may be published or used for teaching.
        We will not put identifiable information on data that are used for these purposes. Taking
        part in this study is your choice. You are free not to take part or to withdraw at any time
        for any reason. No matter what you decide, there will be no penalty or loss of benefit to
        which you are entitled. If you choose to discontinue participation at any time, you will
        still receive SONA participation credit for your time spent actively participating, pro-rated
        at the rate of 0.5 credits for the initial questionnaires, and 0.5 credits for every 6 brief
        app-surveys completed. If you decide to withdraw from this study, the information that you
        have already provided will be kept confidential, specifically all information will be kept
        de-identified. You will also have the option of deleting the app at any point, or asking
        investigators to delete your data. You may choose not to be in the study or to stop being
        in the study before it is over at any time.  This will not affect your class standing or
        your grades at Boston University.  You will not be offered or receive any special consideration
        if you take part in this research study. If you choose to withdraw from the study, we ask
        that you contact study staff (contact information listed on first and last pages of this document).
        Your data will then be permanently deleted from the server on which data is stored, and will
        not be available for analysis in any form. Also, the researcher may take you out of this
        study without your permission.  This may happen because: You do not meet eligibility
        requirements; The researcher thinks it is in your best interest; Other administrative
        reasons. There is also the possibility that questions on study surveys or aspects of
        passive data collection may make you feel uncomfortable. As outlined above, you will be
        able to speak with investigators and/or delete the app at any time should it make you feel
        uncomfortable. You always have the option of refusing to answer any question on any
        questionnaire, whether online or via smartphone, and you have the option of not completing
        any portion of the study. In such a case you can leave the question blank on a questionnaire
        or you can let the researcher know by the email provided that you do not want to answer
        the question. One risk of allowing us to use and store your information for research is
        a potential loss of confidentiality. We will protect your confidentiality by labeling your
        information with a number code and keeping the key linking your number and first name in a
        password-protected platform. Electronic data will be stored on encrypted computers only
        accessible to study staff by password and the appropriate digital credentials. There are no
        known direct benefits for taking part in this study. Data collected in this study has the
        potential to improve the scientific community\'s understanding of how mobile phone-based
        sensors could be used to identify patterns of social activity; which could one day help to
        assess and treat those with mental illness. The alternative is to not participate in this
        study. If you do not wish to participate in this study, there are other studies in which
        you can participate. You can also contact your instructor to learn more about an alternative
        way to fulfill the experimental participation requirement—e.g., through writing a short
        paper. If you have any questions about the PS101 research requirement, please contact Dr.
        Joanne Hebden Palfai, Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, Director of Academic
        Affairs and Undergraduate Studies, at (617) 353-2064 or at jpalfai@bu.edu. There are no
        costs to you for taking part in this research study. If you are injured as a result of
        taking part in this research study, we will assist you in getting medical treatment. However,
        your insurance company will be responsible for the cost. Boston University does not provide
        any other form of compensation for injury. You can call or email us with any concerns or
        questions. If you have questions about your rights as a research subject or want to speak
        with someone independent of the research team, you may contact the Boston University IRB
        directly at 617- 358-6115.  I have read the information in this consent form including
        risks and possible benefits.  I have been given the chance to ask questions.
        My questions have been answered to my satisfaction, and I agree to participate in the study.
    </string>
</resources>